Guide to the William Blackburn Papers, 1859-1985 RL.00115
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
William Blackburn papers
1859-1985
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Blackburn, William, 1899-1972
RL.00115
20 Linear Feet
William Blackburn was a professor of English and creative writing at Duke University. The collection includes correspondence, writings, teaching materials and notes, biographical and family papers, printed materials, scrapbooks, audiovisual material, and photographs from William Blackburn and his family.
15,000 Items
Access Restrictions
RESTRICTED: Selected correspondence is restricted; see container list for details.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The William Blackburn Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift.
Biographical Note
William Blackburn was an author, editor, and professor of English and literary composition at Duke University from 1926 until 1969. Born in 1899 to missionaries in Persia, Blackburn spent his childhood in Seneca, South Carolina, and completed his undergraduate studies at Furman University. He was a Rhodes Scholar at Oxford and received his Ph.D. from Yale University in 1943. His academic scholarship was on Elizabethan poetry; later in his career, he also edited the letters of Joseph Conrad.
Blackburn's influence at Duke, however, stems from his creative writing classes, where he taught and inspired many students who went on to become prominent contemporary writers. His former students include Fred Chappell, William Styron, Reynolds Price, James Applewhite, and Anne Tyler.
Collection Overview
The William Blackburn papers are arranged in the following series: Correspondence; Writings; Teaching Material; Duke University Literary and Artistic Projects; Biographical Data and Family Papers; Printed Material; Scrapbooks; Audiovisual Material; and Photographs. Correspondence includes Blackburn family letters, letters relating to Blackburn's teaching and career at Duke University, and typescripts of letters by and about Joseph Conrad. Writings include Blackburn's own writings and speeches as well as those of students and his son Alexander Lambert Blackburn. Clippings mostly concern Blackburn's academic work, literary events at Duke in which Blackburn was pivotal, and reviews of the work of his students (including Anne Tyler, William Styron, and Reynolds Price). The collection also includes numerous photographs of family members and some of literary figures.
Addition (2007-0129) (200 items; 0.6 lin. ft.; dated 1937-1972) contains correspondence between Blackburn and his daughter, Mary April Blackburn Hill.
Addition (2008-0071) (30 items; 0.1 lin. ft.; 1925-1973) includes correspondence between William Blackburn and his brother, Clark, as well as additional papers from Elizabeth Blackburn. Elizabeth's papers include correspondence and two literary compositions.
Addition (2010-0013) (200 items; 0.6 lin. ft.; dated 1928-1985) includes correspondence between Blackburn and his wife, Elizabeth, especially during the breakup of their marriage; notes about William Blackburn from his son, Alexander Blackburn; articles, speeches, and clippings; and materials from his students and colleagues.
Photographs; American literature -- Study and teaching; Blackburn, William, 1899-1972; Conrad, Joseph, 1857-1924; Duke University. Department of English -- Faculty; Blackburn, William, 1899-1972; Blackburn, Alexander; Blackburn family
- Correspondence, 1859-1974 and n.d.
  Scope and Contents note
  Blackburn's personal and professional correspondence; letters to his students; and correspondence of several members of his family, especially of his son, Alexander Lambert Blackburn, his brothers George and Clark Blackburn, and his first wife Elizabeth Cheney Blackburn. Also contained in the series are copies of letters written by Joseph Conrad to his publishers and much of the correspondence between Blackburn and Reynolds Price.
  - Letters from Various Correspondents
    - Correspondence, 1916-1944, 10 folders (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1956, 11 folders (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1957-1964, 10 folders (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1965-1973 and n.d., 10 folders (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1972 and n.d., 5 folders (Box 5)
  - Early Extended Family Correspondence, 1859-1915 and n.d.
    - Correspondence, 1859-1915 and n.d., 6 folders (Box 5)
  - Correspondence with Alexander Lambert Blackburn, 1938-1974 and n.d.
    - Correspondence, 1938-1946, 9 folders (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1947-1952, 9 folders (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1964, 13 folders (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1965-1974 and n.d., 9 folders (Box 9)
  - Correspondence with Clark and George Blackburn, 1918-1972 and n.d.
    - Correspondence, 1918-1972 and n.d., 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Correspondence with Elizabeth Cheney Blackburn, 1926-1972
    - Correspondence, 1926-1972, 8 folders (Box 10)
  - Letters by and about Joseph Conrad, 1898-1924
    - Letters by and about Conrad, 1898-1924, 8 folders (Box 11)
  - Correspondence with Reynolds Price, 1953-1962
    - Correspondence, 1953-1962, 1 folder (Box 12)
  - Correspondence with William Styron
    - Correspondence, 1944-1973 and n.d. (Box 12)
      Conditions Governing Access note
      [Access Restricted.]
- Writings, 1921-1978 and n.d.
  - Writings by Blackburn
    - Yale University Dissertation (Box 13)
      - Matthew Arnold's Literature and Dogma: An Essay Towards a Better Apprehension of the Bible, 1943 (Box 13)
    - Monographs and Edited Books
      - Letters of Joseph Conrad to William Blackwood and David S. Meldrum, TS Drafts of Blackburn's apparatus, 1958 (Box 13)
      - [Houghton-Mifflin Anthology of English Literature], Correspondence and Questionnaire, 1947 (Box 13)
      - [Houghton-Mifflin Anthology of English Literature], TS copies of selected poems, 1947 (Box 13)
      - [Houghton-Mifflin Anthology of English Literature], TS copies of selected works, 1947 (Box 13)
    - Essays
      - Academic essays, 1930-1948 and n.d. (Box 13)
      - Academic essays: Lady Magdalen Herbert and her Son George, Proof TS drafts, publication correspondence and notes, 1947-1951 and n.d. (Box 13)
      - Non-academic essays and articles, 1928-1945 and n.d. (Box 13)
      - An Awareness of the Arts: An Essay in Retrospect, Duke Alumni Register, April 1963 (Box 14)
    - Addresses and Lectures
      - Addresses and lectures, 1921; 1942 and n.d. (Box 14)
    - Book Reviews
      - Book reviews by Blackburn, 1946-1962 (Box 14)
      - Book review of Blackburn's Letters of Joseph Conrad to William Blackwood and Devid S. Meldrum, 1959 (Box 14)
    - Blackburn's Appearance on ABC's Meet the Professor, 1963
      - ABC press release, 1963 (2 copies) (Box 14)
      - Partial transcript, published in Mississippi Quarterly 31, 1978 (Box 14)
    - Notes and Fragments, n.d. (Box 14)
    - Duke University Research Council
      - Correspondence and grants, 1946-1955 and n.d. (Box 14)
  - Writings by Others
    - Alexander Lambert Blackburn, Diary of a Blackburn at Camp Desert Rock Operation, October 1957 (Box 14)
    - Alexander Lambert Blackburn, TS draft, The Earthly Comedy, 1971 (2 copies) (Box 14)
    - Alexander Lambert Blacburn, ed., Sight 1, June 1953 (Box 14)
    - Alexander Lambert Blackburn, ed., Writers Forum 5, 1978 (Box 14)
    - Fred Chappell, Six Propositions about Literature and History, New Literary History 1, 1970 (Box 14)
    - Guy Davenport, The Aeroplanes at Brescia, The Hudson Review, n.d. (Box 14)
    - Mac Hyman, ed., William Blackburn, TS draft, Love, Boy, n.d. (1), no apparatus (Box 14)
    - Mac Hyman, ed., Blackburn, Love, Boy (2), Hyman to Angelo and Jo Bettoya, 1956-1962 and n.d. (Box 14)
    - Mac Hyman, ed., Blackburn, Love, Boy (3), Hyman to Blackburn, 1947-1963 (Box 14)
    - Mac Hyman, ed., Blackburn, Love, Boy (4), Hyman to James Oliver Brown, 1953-1963 (Box 14)
    - Mac Hyman, ed., Blackburn, Love, Boy (5), Hyman to Dinah and Mitzi Hyman, 1953-1959 and n.d. (Box 15)
    - Mac Hyman, ed., Blackburn, Love, Boy (6), Hyman to his parents, 1943-1950 (Box 15)
    - Mac Hyman, ed., Blackburn, Love, Boy (7), Hyman to his wife, 1952-1962 and n.d. (Box 15)
    - Mac Hyman, ed., Blackburn, Love, Boy (8), Hyman to Alvin G. Manuel, 1957-1961 and n.d. (Box 15)
    - Mac Hyman, ed., Blackburn, Love, Boy (9), Hyman to Random House, Inc., 1954-1960 (Box 15)
    - Mac Hyman, ed., Blackburn, Love, Boy (10), Hyman to Henry Maxwell Steele, 1954-1962 and n.d. (Box 15)
    - Harry R. Jackson, TS draft, Report on Allen Building Takeover, 1969 (Box 15)
    - Diane Kelekyan, TS draft, William Styron: The Child in the Writer, 1972 (Box 15)
    - Kathryn Vale, A Grain, Perhaps of Wheat, 1964 (Box 15)
- Course Material, 11 boxes
  - Lectures, Notes, and Research Clippings
    Arrangement note
    Alpha by subject; quotation marks denote instances in which Blackburn's folder titles have been retained.
    - Joseph Additson and Sir Richard Steele (Box 15)
    - Matthew Arnold (Box 15)
    - Matthew Arnold and Baruch Spinoza (Box 15)
    - Thomas Arnold (Box 15)
    - Jane Austen (Box 15)
    - Francis Beaumont and John Fletcher (Box 15)
    - Bibliography (Box 15)
    - William Blake (Box 15)
    - Sir Thomas Browne (1 of 2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Sir Thomas Browne (2 of 2 folders) (Box 16)
    - Robert Browning (2 folders) (Box 16)
    - John Bunyan (Box 16)
    - Fanny Burney (Box 16)
    - Robert Burns (Box 16)
    - George Gordon, Lord Byron (Box 16)
    - Thomas Campion (Box 16)
    - Thomas Carlyle (4 of 5 folders) (Box 16)
    - Thomas Carlyle (5 of 5 folders) (Box 17)
    - Thomas Carlyle and German Literature (Box 17)
    - Thomas Carlyle, Past and Present (Box 17)
    - Benvenuto Cellini (2 folders) (Box 17)
    - Philip Dormer Stanhope, Lord Chesterfield (Box 17)
    - Samuel Taylor Coleridge (Box 17)
    - William Collins (Box 17)
    - William Congreve (Box 17)
    - Joseph Conrad (Box 17)
    - William Cowper (Box 17)
    - Daniel Defoe (Box 17)
    - Charles Dickens (Box 17)
    - John Donne (1 of 2 folders) (Box 17)
    - John Donne (2 of 2 folders) (Box 18)
    - John Donne and Izaak Walton (Box 18)
    - John Dryden (2 folders) (Box 18)
    - Early English drama (Box 18)
    - T.S. Eliot (2 folders) (Box 18)
    - Elizabethan Prose (Box 18)
    - Notes for English 56, The Short Story (Box 18)
    - Essays on Eighteenth-Century Thought (Box 18)
    - Henry Fielding, Tom Jones (Box 18)
    - Gustave Flaubert (Box 18)
    - John Fletcher (Box 18)
    - John Ford (Box 18)
    - E.M. Forster (Box 18)
    - Freud and Literature (Box 18)
    - ... from Novelists (Box 18)
    - Gawain-poet (Box 18)
    - John Gay (Box 18)
    - God and the Bible (Box 18)
    - Oliver Goldsmith (Box 18)
    - Thomas Gray (Box 18)
    - Robert Greene (Box 18)
    - Greek Tragedy (Box 18)
    - The Harrowing of Hell in Medieval Drama (Box 18)
    - William Hazlitt (Box 19)
    - Thomas Heywood (Box 19)
    - Aldous Huxley (Box 19)
    - Jacobean Drama: Jonson to Shirley (Box 19)
    - Samuel Johnson (Box 19)
    - Ben Jonson (Box 19)
    - Ben Jonson, The Alchemist (Box 19)
    - Ben Jonson, Volpone (Box 19)
    - Ben Jonson and John Donne (Box 19)
    - Ben Jonson's Poetry (Box 19)
    - James Joyce (Box 19)
    - John Keats (Box 19)
    - Henry King and Milton's Lycidas (Box 19)
    - Thomas Kyd (Box 19)
    - Charles Lamb (Box 19)
    - William Langland, Piers Plowman (Box 19)
    - D.H. Lawrence (Box 19)
    - T.E. Lawrence (Box 20)
    - Thomas Babington Macaulay (Box 20)
    - Niccolo Machiavelli (Box 20)
    - Christopher Marlowe, Doctor Faustus (Box 20)
    - Christopher Marlowe, Edward II (Box 20)
    - Christopher Marlowe, Hero and Leander (Box 20)
    - Christopher Marlowe, The Jew of Malta (Box 20)
    - Christopher Marlowe, Tamburlaine (Box 20)
    - Andrew Marvell (Box 20)
    - Philip Massinger (Box 20)
    - Thomas Middleton (Box 20)
    - Thomas Middleton, Blurt, Master Constable, and Michaelmas Terme (Box 20)
    - John Milton (Box 20)
    - John Milton, Areopagitica (Box 20)
    - John Milton, Paradise Lost (Box 20)
    - John Milton, Samson Agonistes (2 folders) (Box 21)
    - Minor Poets of the Seventeenth Century (Box 21)
    - Minor Victorian Poets (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous: Religious Essays (Box 21)
    - Michel de Montaigne (Box 21)
    - Sir Thomas More (Box 21)
    - Thomas Nashe (Box 21)
    - Margaret Lucas, Daughter of Newcastle (Box 21)
    - Sir Thomas North (Box 21)
    - Sean O'Casey, Juno and the Paycock (Box 21)
    - Charles Osgood, The Voice of England (Box 21)
    - Sir Thomas Overbury (Box 21)
    - Pearl and Sir Gawain and the Green Knight (Box 21)
    - Samuel Pepys (Box 21)
    - Periodicals of the Eighteenth and Nineteenth Centuries (Box 21)
    - Francis Petrarch (Box 21)
    - Alexander Pope (Box 21)
    - Alexander Pope: Lecture Notes (Box 21)
    - Portraits (Box 21)
    - Pre-Shakespearean Drama (Box 21)
    - Ernest Renan (Box 21)
    - Samuel Richardson (Box 21)
    - Restoration Poets and Dramatists (Box 21)
    - Thomas Sackville (Box 21)
    - St. Paul and Protestantism (Box 21)
    - Sir Walter Scott (Box 22)
    - Sir Walter Scott, Ivanhoe (Box 22)
    - Second Shepherd's Play (Box 22)
    - Seventeenth-Century Poets: Notes and Essays (Box 22)
    - Seventeenth-Century Prose (Box 22)
    - Richard Brinsley Sheridan (Box 22)
    - William Shakespeare, 1 and 2 Henry IV (Box 22)
    - William Shakespeare, Hamlet (Box 22)
    - William Shakespeare, King Lear (Box 22)
    - William Shakespeare, Othello (Box 22)
    - William Shakespeare, Romeo and Juliet (Box 22)
    - William Shakespeare, Troilus and Cressida (Box 22)
    - William Shakespeare, Venus and Adonis (Box 22)
    - George Bernard Shaw (Box 22)
    - Percy Shelley (Box 22)
    - Sir Philip Sidney (2 folders) (Box 22)
    - Tobias Smollett (Box 23)
    - Edmund Spenser, The Faerie Queene (Box 23)
    - Edmund Spenser's Shorter Poetry (Box 23)
    - Baruch Spinoza (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - Sir Richard Steele (Box 23)
    - John Sterling (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - Laurence Sterne (Box 23)
    - Lytton Strachey (Box 23)
    - Lytton Strachey, Elizabeth and Essex (Box 23)
    - Lytton Strachley, Queen Victoria (Box 24)
    - Henry Howard, Earl of Surrey and Sir Thomas Wyatt (Box 24)
    - Jonathan Swift (Box 24)
    - Alfred, Lord Tennyson and Robert Browning-Bibliography (Box 24)
    - William Makepeace Thackeray (Box 24)
    - William Makepeace Thackeray, Henry Esmond (Box 24)
    - James Thomson (Box 24)
    - Cyril Tourneur, The Revenger's Tragedy (Box 24)
    - C.F. Tucker Brooke and Shakespeare (Box 24)
    - Tudor Drama (Box 24)
    - Victorian England (Box 24)
    - The Wakefield Master (Box 24)
    - Wakefield Second Shepherd's Play (Box 24)
    - Horace Walpole, Letters (Box 24)
    - Izaak Walton (Box 24)
    - Thomas Warton the Elder; Josiah Warton; Thomas Warton the Younger (Box 24)
    - John Webster, The Duchess of Malfi (Box 24)
    - John Webster, The White Devil (Box 24)
    - William Wordsworth (Box 25)
    - Sir Thomas Wyatt (Box 25)
    - Edward Young (Box 25)
  - Student Writings
    - Essays, 1950 and n.d. (Box 25)
    - Poetry, 1937 and n.d. (Box 25)
    - Short Stories, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Exams, Tests, and Quizzes
    - English 143, 1944-1956 and n.d. (Box 25)
    - English 144, 1945-1965 and n.d. (Box 25)
    - English 143 and English 144, unidentified and n.d. (Box 25)
    - English S-157, 1950 (Box 25)
  - Course Evaluations and Teaching Testimonials
    - Evaluations and testimonials, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Duke University Administrative and Departmental Memoranda
    - Memoranda, 1938 and n.d. (Box 25)
  - Miscellany
    - Miscellaneous material relating to Blackburn's students, 1951-1952 and n.d. (Box 25)
- Duke University Literary and Artistic Projects, 1 box
  - One and Twenty: Duke Narrative and Verse, 1924-1945 (Box 25)
    - Correspondence related to compilation and publication, 1944-1945 (2 folders) (Box 25)
  - Commentary on the Archive
    - Clippings and memoranda related to the Archive, 1953-1977 and n.d. (Box 25)
  - Duke Film Society
    - Memoranda, 1950-1952 (Box 25)
  - Durham Literary Arts Festival
    - Clippings, correspondence related to the festival, 1959-1971 and n.d. (Box 25)
- Biographical Data and Family Papers, 3 boxes
  - Legal and Financial Papers (Box 26)
    - Blackburn's passports, 1923-1970 (Box 26)
    - Alien regisration documents for Blackburn's residences in Oxford and in Paris, 1923 and 1925 (Box 26)
    - Blackburn's notices of rank and salary, Duke University, 1933-1968 (Box 26)
    - Elizabeth Cheney Blackburn's response to Blackburn's divorce action, 1951 (Box 26)
    - Blackburn's Duke pay stubs, 1954-1969 (Box 26)
    - Blackburn's federal and North Carolina state income tax returns, 1959-1965 (Box 26)
    - Wachovia trust agreement, 1963-1964 (Box 26)
    - Life insurance premium contribution notice, n.d. (Box 26)
  - Family Papers
    - Blackburn
      - Academic records
        - Academic records, 1921-1943 and n.d. (Box 26)
          Grade reports are restricted.
      - Material relating to Blackburn's life at Furman
        - The Bonhomie, 1921 (Box 26)
        - Buzzing Boosters Club, 1920 and n.d. (Box 26)
        - Campus and intercollegiate oratorical contests, 1920-1921 (Box 26)
        - Commencement, 1921 (Box 26)
        - Furman Glee Club programs, notices, 1918-1920 and n.d. (Box 26)
        - The Furman Hornet, 1921 February 19 (Box 26)
        - Pi Kappa Alpha Fraternity, 1921 and n.d. (Box 26)
        - Miscellany, 1921 and n.d. (Box 26)
      - Material relating to Blackburn's life in Florence
        - 1945 and n.d. (Box 26)
        - Blackburn's return to the U.S. aboard the USS Randolph, 1945 and n.d. (Box 26)
      - Material relating to Blackburn's publications, 1969 and n.d. (Box 26)
      - Material relating to Blackburn's Rhodes Scholarship, 1919-1924 (Box 26)
    - Blackburn's Family
      - Alexander Lambert Blackburn
        - Academic records, 1944-1955 (Box 26)
        - Material relating his life at the Phillips Academy, 1946-1947 and n.d. (Box 26)
        - Material relating to his life at Yale, 1948 (Box 26)
      - Clark Waring Blackburn
        - Material relating to his life in Greenville, South Carolina, 1938 (Box 26)
      - George Stebbins Blackburn
        - Academic records, 1919 (Box 26)
        - Material relating to his life at Furman, 1920-1922 (Box 26)
        - Material relating to his life at Yale, 1925-1926 (2 folders) (Box 26)
        - Material relating to his work as an educator, 1935-1942 (Box 26)
      - Mary April Blackburn
        - Material relating to her education, 1944-1947 (Box 26)
      - George Cole Stebbins
        - Material relating to his work in the ministry, 1931 and 1942(?) (Box 26)
      - Clark Waring
        - Academic records, 1906 and 1908 (Box 26)
  - Writings By and For Family Members
    - Author unidentified-Notebook, 1896(?) (Box 27)
    - Authors unidentified, 1882, 1894, 1945, and n.d. (Box 27)
    - Blackburn, 1945 and n.d. (Box 27)
    - Blackburn, Biography, n.d. (Box 27)
    - Alexander Lambert Blackburn, 1939-1968 and n.d. (Box 27)
    - Amy Waring Blackburn
      - William Blackburn's Baby Book, 1900 (Box 27)
      - Journal, chronicling William Blackburn's infancy and daily life in Persia, 1900-1904 (Box 27)
      - Short stories, 1912 (Box 27)
    - Charles Stanley Blackburn--Biography, n.d. (Box 27)
    - Charles Stanley Blackburn and Amy Waring Blackburn--Biography, 1896 (Box 27)
    - Charles Stanley and Amy Waring Blackburn, records of missionary work in Persia, 1897-1902 and n.d. (Box 27)
    - David Blackburn, 1971 (Box 27)
    - William Maxwell Blackburn--Biography, 1899 and n.d. (Box 27)
    - William Maxwell Blackburn
      - Constantine the Great, 1868(?) (Box 27)
      - Oliver Cromwell, 1873(?) (Box 27)
      - Maps and Charts for Bible History, January 1880 (Box 27)
      - Notes on geology and natural history, 1874(?)-1896(?) (1 of 2 folders) (Box 27)
      - Notes on geology and natural history, 1874(?)-1896(?) (2 of 2 folders) (Box 28)
      - Notes on religion, n.d. (Box 28)
      - Queen Elizabeth and the Reformation, 1885(?) (Box 28)
    - Eugene Grant, n.d. (Box 28)
    - Linn Taylor, n.d. (Box 28)
    - Malvina Waring, 1889(?) and n.d. (Box 28)
  - William Blackburn Scholarship Fund, 1973-1985 (Box 28)
  - Blackburn memorial service, 1972 (Box 28)
  - Blackburn tribute, Duke Alumni Register
    - Winter 1973 (Box 28)
    - Partial clipping, Winter 1973 (Box 28)
  - Miscellany and Memorabilia
    - Poems collected by Blackburn, 1916-1919 and n.d. (Box 28)
    - Blackburn--Poetry readings, 1956, 1965 and n.d. (Box 28)
    - Blackburn--Donations to Perkins Library, Duke University, 1969 and 1977 (Box 28)
    - Miscellany, n.d. (Box 28)
    - Memorabilia, 1862-1921 and n.d. (Box 28)
- Clippings, 1 box
  - Clippings related to life at Furman, his Rhodes Scholarship (Box 28)
  - Clippings related to Duke, life in Durham (Box 28)
  - Clippings related to his family (Box 28)
  - Clippings of reviews of his writings (Box 28)
  - Articles by and about Blackburn's students (Box 28)
- Printed Material, 2 boxes
  - Periodicals (Box 28)
    - The American Oxonian, April 1946 (Box 28)
    - The Furman Echo (Box 29)
      - December 1917 (Box 29)
      - June 1919 (Box 29)
      - April 1921 (2 copies) (Box 29)
      - October 1921 (Box 29)
    - The Furman Magazine, Spring 1972 (Box 29)
    - Historical Bulletin of Huron College, Pierre University, and Scotland Academy, 1920 (2 copies, 1 without a cover) (Box 29)
    - Huron College Bulletin, May 24, 1920 (Box 29)
    - Modern Fiction Studies, February 1955 (Box 29)
    - St. Andrew's Review, 1972 (Box 29)
    - Sight, June 1953 (Box 29)
  - Periodicals published by Duke University
    - The Archive, January 1949 (Box 29)
    - Duke Alumni Register
      - April 1963 (2 copies) (Box 29)
      - November 1968 (Box 29)
      - Winter 1973 (Box 29)
    - Duke 'n' Duchess
      - October 1950 (Box 29)
      - [December 1950?] (Box 29)
    - The Friends of Duke University Library, 1971 (2 copies) (Box 29)
  - Periodicals published by students
    - Inner Chords, 1971 (Box 29)
  - University Press Catalogues, 1938-1964 (Box 29)
  - Miscellany, 1907-1968 and n.d. (Box 29)
  - Anthologies with Annotations by Blackburn (Box 29)
- Scrapbooks, 4 boxes
  - Photo album of missionary work in Persia, [1896-1903] (Box 29)
  - Cartoons, n.d. (Box 29)
  - Family photo albums and two scrapbooks (Box 30)
  - Scrapbook (Box 44)
  - Cartoons, n.d. (Box 31)
- Audio/Visual, 4 boxes
  - 3.75 ips audio tape of Blackburn lecturing on the letters of Mac Hyman, 14 November 1969 (Box 31)
  - 3.75 ips audio tape of Blackburn memorial service, 17 December 1973 (Box 31)
  - VHS copy of Blackburn's appearance on ABC's Meet the Professor, 1963 (Box 32)
  - Beta copy of Blackburn's appearance on ABC's Meet the Professor, 1963 (Box 33)
  - 16mm film of Blackburn's appearance on ABC's Meet the Professor, 1963 (Box 34)
- Photographs, 3 boxes
  Includes unsorted and unarranged photographs of family members, travels, student portraits, and other events from Blackburn and his family's life.
  - Photographs and postcards of students, family, travels (Box 35)
  - Photographs and postcards of students, family, travels (Box 36)
  - Photographs and postcards of students, family, travels (Box 37)